So far you've learned a lot about car sensors, and
これまで車両のセンサーについて そしてPythonで一般的なフィルターを
also about how to implement a Kalman filter in Python.
実装する方法について 多くを学んできました
And we also expect that you've got enough of a grasp on C++ to the point
また C++について十分に理解し カルマンを実装して
where you can now implement a Kalman filter in it.
フィルターリングできるように なったはずです
In this lesson you're going to combine all of this knowledge
このレッスンでは これらすべての知識を組み合わせて
to develop a complete fusion model.
完全なフュージョンモデルを開発します
There are many pieces in a Kalman filter based sense of fusion, so
フュージョンの カルマンフィルターベースの感知には
I want to quickly show you a general map of what you'll be building.
多くの要素が含まれるため これから構築物の概要をお見せします
Don't worry if you don't follow everything yet.
まだすべてを理解できなくても 心配は要りません
You'll see this map again.
このマップは後でまた確認します
First off,
まずは
you're going to build something called an Extended Kalman Filter.
拡張カルマンフィルターと呼ばれるものを 構築します
It's extended in the sense that it will be capable of handling
拡張されたのは より複雑なモーションモデルや
more complex motion models and measurement models.
測定モデルを扱えるように なった点です
And here is the overall processing flow.
これが全体的な処理フローです
You have two sensors, a lidar and a radar.
ライダーとレーダーの 2つのセンサーがあります
The information provided by these sensors is used to estimate the state
これらのセンサーから提供される情報は 移動中の歩行者の状態を
of a moving pedestrian, and
推定するために使用され
this state is represented by a 2D position and a 2D velocity.
歩行者の状態は2D位置と2D速度で 表されます
Each time we receive new measurements from a given sensor,
特定のセンサーから 新しい測定値を受け取るたびに
the estimation function is triggered.
推定機能がトリガーされます
At this point we perform two steps, State Prediction and Measurement Update.
この時点で状態予測と測定値更新という 2つのステップを実行します
In the Prediction step, we predict the pedestrian state and its covariance.
予測ステップでは共分散で 歩行者の状態を予測します
We do so by taking into account the elapsed time between the current and
この予測では 前回の観測から現在の観測までの
the previous observations.
経過時間を考慮します
The measurement update step depends on sensor type.
測定更新ステップは センサーのタイプによって異なります
There are two cases that we'll see, Laser and Radar.
レーザーとレーダーという 2つのケースがあります
If the current measurements are generated by a laser sensor,
現在の測定値が レーザーセンサーによって生成された場合は
then we just apply a standard Kalman filter to update the pedestrian's state.
標準の共通フィルターを適用して 歩行者の状態を更新します
However, radar measurements involve a nonlinear measurement function.
ただし レーダー測定には 非線形測定関数が含まれます
So when we receive radar measurements,
そのためレーダー測定値を受け取ると
we use different tweaks to handle the measurement update.
さまざまな微調整を行って 測定値の更新を処理します
For instance,
たとえば
we may use Extended Kalman filter equations, which you'll see later.
拡張カルマンフィルターの式を使用します これについては後で説明します
Does that sound like fun?
面白そうでしょ？
Let's get started.
それでは始めましょう